<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Zerodha Tech Blog</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Zerodha Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zerodha.tech/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1.5+ million PDFs in 25 minutes</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/1-5-million-pdfs-in-25-minutes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/1-5-million-pdfs-in-25-minutes/</guid><description>At Zerodha, many million users login and use our financial platforms every day. Over the recent months, on an average day, 1.5+ million users have been executing stock and derivative transactions. On a volatile day, this number could easily double. After a trading session concludes and all the number-crunching, tallying, and “backoffice” operations are completed—with file dumps received from stock exchanges and other market infrastructure institutions—stock brokers e-mail a digitally signed PDF report called the contract note to every user who transacted on that particular day.</description></item><item><title>Logging at Zerodha</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/logging-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/logging-at-zerodha/</guid><description>At Zerodha, we run a multitude of internal and public-facing services that generate copious amounts of logs. While developers use these logs to debug or troubleshoot incidents, some services also emit logs that must be persisted for prolonged periods to comply with numerous regulatory requirements. In this post, I will delve into our experiences with the ELK stack, why it didn&amp;rsquo;t fit our needs and our migration to ClickHouse.
Why ELK wasn’t the right fit for us In 2018, we adopted the ELK stack as our de facto stack for storing application logs.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure monitoring with Prometheus at Zerodha</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/infra-monitoring-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/infra-monitoring-at-zerodha/</guid><description>On any given day, we handle around 15% of daily retail trading volume across all stock exchanges in India. Billions of requests generated in the process are handled by a suite of systems we have built in-house. Also, we are very particular on self-hosting as many dependencies as possible, everything from CRMs to large databases, Kafka clusters, mail servers etc.
To aid these primary systems, there are a large number of ancillary workloads that run, covering everything from real-time trades, document processing, KYC, and account opening, legal and compliance, complex, large scale P&amp;amp;L and number crunching, and a wide range of backoffice workloads.</description></item></channel></rss>