<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scaling on Zerodha Tech Blog</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/tags/scaling/</link><description>Recent content in scaling on Zerodha Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 15:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zerodha.tech/tags/scaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scaling with common sense #2: Being future ready.</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/being-future-ready-with-common-sense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 15:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/being-future-ready-with-common-sense/</guid><description>Over the last year, owing to the unexpected rally in capital markets, Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s customer base has more than tripled, significantly increasing the number of concurrent users on our platforms along with the traffic and load they generate on numerous systems in the background. For context, in January 2020, we were handling 2+ million retail trades daily. In April 2020, it had risen to 7+ million. Today, it goes up to 12+ million.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with common sense</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/scaling-with-common-sense/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/scaling-with-common-sense/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Scaling&amp;rdquo; is not a specific technique but an entire spectrum that stretches all the way from &amp;ldquo;Google scale&amp;rdquo; to the K8s cluster Karan runs on a Raspberry Pi plugged into a 12V shaver outlet in his bathroom to encrypt his DNS queries for peak privacy, while he asks Alexa to dim the lights and play his favorite non-mainstream indie music.
It is a collection of practices unique and intimate to every organisation, and is the product of an infinite number of variables; the numerous domain-specific problems, the structure of the organisation, the nature of the people involved and their biases, countless engineering decisions and trade-offs, technical debt and history, ad infinitum.</description></item></channel></rss>