<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>philosophy on Zerodha Tech Blog</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in philosophy on Zerodha Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zerodha.tech/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scaling with common sense</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/scaling-with-common-sense/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/scaling-with-common-sense/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Scaling&amp;rdquo; is not one technique but a spectrum that stretches all the way up from &amp;ldquo;Google scale&amp;rdquo; to the K8s cluster Karan runs on a Raspberry Pi plugged into a 12V shaver outlet in his bathroom to encrypt his DNS queries for peak privacy, while he asks Alexa to dim the lights and play his favorite non-mainstream indie music.
It is a collection of practices unique and intimate to every organisation, and is the product of an infinite number of variables; the numerous domain-specific problems, the structure of the organisation, the nature of the people involved and their biases, countless engineering decisions and trade-offs, technical debt and history, ad infinitum.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://zerodha.tech/blog/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zerodha.tech/blog/hello-world/</guid><description>Zerodha, now India&amp;rsquo;s largest stock broker, bootstrapped and profitable, turns ten years old this year. The Zerodha tech team turns seven years old. The tech team has remained largely elusive over the course of our existence. While we have pondered starting a tech blog for more than half a decade, we have often found ourselves too busy building the fundamental blocks underlying a stock brokerage. We have also been stalled by a sense of unpreparedness to talk to the world about our very unconventional setup.</description></item></channel></rss>